<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Kevin Dublin | Educator, Writer, Programmer - Audio, Poetry, Spoken Word</title><link href="https://kevindublin.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://kevindublin.com/feeds/audio-poetry-spoken-word.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://kevindublin.com/</id><updated>2015-05-22T01:06:00-07:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Poems from Courting Sylvia Plath</title><link href="https://kevindublin.com/courting-sylvia-plath.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-05-22T01:06:00-07:00</published><updated>2015-05-22T01:06:00-07:00</updated><author><name>kevin</name></author><id>tag:kevindublin.com,2015-05-22:/courting-sylvia-plath.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;



&lt;iframe src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/playlists/106211447&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&amp;amp;visual=true" width="100%" height="450" frameborder="no" scrolling="no"&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've had about half of the poems from my series on Sylvia Plath, "Courting Sylvia Plath" published over in the literary journal &lt;a href="http://menacinghedge.com/spring2015/entry-dublin.php"&gt;Menacing Hedge&lt;/a&gt;. To celebrate, I've posted recordings of three of the poems to Soundcloud. You can listen to "At a Euro Cafe in East Village," "An Affair on …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;



&lt;iframe src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/playlists/106211447&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&amp;amp;visual=true" width="100%" height="450" frameborder="no" scrolling="no"&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've had about half of the poems from my series on Sylvia Plath, "Courting Sylvia Plath" published over in the literary journal &lt;a href="http://menacinghedge.com/spring2015/entry-dublin.php"&gt;Menacing Hedge&lt;/a&gt;. To celebrate, I've posted recordings of three of the poems to Soundcloud. You can listen to "At a Euro Cafe in East Village," "An Affair on Hampstead Heath," and "Fragments" from "Courting Sylvia Plath" below and follow along in the lit journal after reading a preface to the work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.kevindublin.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/plath.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="courting-sylvia-plath" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-100397" height="300" src="http://www.kevindublin.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/plath.jpg" width="500"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Audio, Poetry, Spoken Word"></category><category term="courting sylvia plath"></category><category term="poems"></category><category term="publications"></category></entry><entry><title>One Art | Elizabeth Bishop</title><link href="https://kevindublin.com/one-art-elizabeth-bishop.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-05-12T12:41:00-07:00</published><updated>2013-05-12T12:41:00-07:00</updated><author><name>kevin</name></author><id>tag:kevindublin.com,2013-05-12:/one-art-elizabeth-bishop.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One Art&lt;/strong&gt; | Elizabeth Bishop&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The art of losing isn’t hard to master;&lt;br&gt;
so many things seem filled with the intent&lt;br&gt;
to be lost that their loss is no disaster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lose something every day. Accept the fluster&lt;br&gt;
of lost door keys, the hour badly spent.&lt;br&gt;
The art of losing isn …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One Art&lt;/strong&gt; | Elizabeth Bishop&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The art of losing isn’t hard to master;&lt;br&gt;
so many things seem filled with the intent&lt;br&gt;
to be lost that their loss is no disaster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lose something every day. Accept the fluster&lt;br&gt;
of lost door keys, the hour badly spent.&lt;br&gt;
The art of losing isn’t hard to master.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then practice losing farther, losing faster:&lt;br&gt;
places, and names, and where it was you meant&lt;br&gt;
to travel. None of these will bring disaster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I lost my mother’s watch. And look! my last, or&lt;br&gt;
next-to-last, of three loved houses went.&lt;br&gt;
The art of losing isn’t hard to master.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I lost two cities, lovely ones. And, vaster,&lt;br&gt;
some realms I owned, two rivers, a continent.&lt;br&gt;
I miss them, but it wasn’t a disaster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—Even losing you (the joking voice, a gesture&lt;br&gt;
I love) I shan’t have lied. It’s evident&lt;br&gt;
the art of losing’s not too hard to master&lt;br&gt;
though it may look like (&lt;em&gt;Write it&lt;/em&gt;!) like disaster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=http%3A%2F%2Fapi.soundcloud.com%2Ftracks%2F95129688" height="100" width="400" frameborder="no" scrolling="no"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think it's fitting that I post this on Mother's Day. Loss is the most universal, prevalent, primal feeling human’s experience. Some might say it is love, but I would argue that we’re keenly aware when we lose something and may not be aware when we love something (or someone). Combine that with a masterful, seamless poetic display in one of the most difficult verse forms to master in English (that isn’t redundant game-playing-- I'm looking at you sestina) and you will have what I might consider the best poem I’ve ever read, Elizabeth Bishop’s “One Art.” It’s so unassuming, so simple, yet so complex. Hearing this poem read aloud for the first time in a Forms of Poetry classroom read wonderfully by Poet/Professor Michael White changed my life. Not in one of those hyperbolic, 21^st^ century teenager ways either. Before that class I was more interested in poetry as expression, poetry as philosophy, and, mostly, poetry as performance. I wanted to cry after he finished reading it. It was a release. Later, re-reading it, I did cry. I became obsessed with Bishop afterwards; I fell in love with the dead lesbian who shook me into wanting to become the poet that I want to be. I devoured everything: her poems, prose, biography, art, and letters. I saved bits of each, so that I might one day discover something “new.” So I may be a bit bias. To the point, “One Art” is a villanelle. If you think about Bishop’s biography, then this poem is usually connected to her time abroad in Brazil, her mother’s insanity and later death, her return to America from Brazil, an ex-lover’s (Lota de Macedo Soares’) suicide, and an estrangement from a young lover, Alice Methfessel. I believe the poem is about all of these things and none of them. It’s a writing through, universal sort of poem that requires no context, but becomes even richer once you have it. “One Art” is from Bishop’s final collection, &lt;em&gt;Geography III&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Audio, Poetry, Spoken Word"></category><category term="Elizabeth Bishop Sunday"></category><category term="NPM"></category><category term="poetry"></category></entry><entry><title>Red Like Our Room Used to Feel</title><link href="https://kevindublin.com/red-like-our-room.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-05-06T05:05:00-07:00</published><updated>2013-05-06T05:05:00-07:00</updated><author><name>kevin</name></author><id>tag:kevindublin.com,2013-05-06:/red-like-our-room.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;So first off, the website went down during April. I was in the process of moving hosts and screwed up. I wasn't able to take the time to get it back up until now. Meaning, the NPM posts I had planned never happened. I think I'll just randomly post some …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So first off, the website went down during April. I was in the process of moving hosts and screwed up. I wasn't able to take the time to get it back up until now. Meaning, the NPM posts I had planned never happened. I think I'll just randomly post some of the choices. In the meantime, here's a spoken word album that's inspired me to do something similar (hopefully) in the next few weeks and post it online:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enjoy. Learn more about &lt;a href="http://ryanvanwinkle.com/about/" title="Poet!"&gt;Ryan Van Winkle&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe style="position: relative; display: block; width: 300px; height: 410px;" src="http://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/v=2/album=1932211965/size=grande3/bgcol=FFFFFF/linkcol=010e19/transparent=true/" height="410" width="300" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content><category term="Audio, Poetry, Spoken Word"></category></entry></feed>