<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Kevin Dublin | Educator, Writer, Programmer - Poetry, Random</title><link href="https://kevindublin.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://kevindublin.com/feeds/poetry-random.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://kevindublin.com/</id><updated>2012-11-09T00:12:00-08:00</updated><entry><title>I'm an eBook Convert</title><link href="https://kevindublin.com/im-an-ebook-convert.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-11-09T00:12:00-08:00</published><updated>2012-11-09T00:12:00-08:00</updated><author><name>kevin</name></author><id>tag:kevindublin.com,2012-11-09:/im-an-ebook-convert.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;As a Kindle Fire owner and as someone who just left the vast majority of his books on the other side of the country, I’ve realized the truth. Printed books are a luxury. The rich (or moderately well-off) can have their books shipped or placed in storage; the old …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As a Kindle Fire owner and as someone who just left the vast majority of his books on the other side of the country, I’ve realized the truth. Printed books are a luxury. The rich (or moderately well-off) can have their books shipped or placed in storage; the old do not move their books; the young do not buy books, but they borrow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With quality eBooks, I get the content I enjoy, and it’s cheaper, accessible faster, and all in one place. It’s not even just books. I send articles to my Kindle as documents via the web add-on, &lt;a href="http://www.readability.com/kevdublin/latest" title="Readibility"&gt;Readibility&lt;/a&gt;. It’s wonderful. As someone who doesn’t have a lot of money and who plans to move around a lot for (at least) the next five to seven years, eBooks just make sense. Amazon, your fully-integrated content system has done it. I’m a convert. Heck, I’m even going to start publishing chapbooks and books as eBooks via my micro press. Now, if only I could solve two problems:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How can I force publishers to embrace publishing more poetry as eBooks?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How can I get authors to sign my Kindle?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><category term="Poetry, Random"></category></entry></feed>